Hyung-Kwon Ko

College of Computing KAIST, Daejeon hyungkwonko@gmail.com https://hyungkwonko.info

About

Hyung-Kwon Ko is a researcher at KAIST Interaction Lab. His main research areas include Human-Computer Interaction, Human-Centered AI, and Information Visualization. He designs and develops interactive systems using AI to innovate people's working paradigm, in turn, changing their lives more intelligently and conveniently. Recently, he is interested in how foundation models (e.g., DALL-E) could help people in visual art domains perform creative works.

Education

2019-2021	Seoul National University , Seoul, Korea Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Advisor: Jinwook Seo)
2014-2019	Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Industrial Engineering

Publications

Conference & Journal Papers

[a5] Ko, H.-K.*, An, S.*, Park, G., Kim, S.K., Kim, D., Kim, B., Seo, J. (2022).

> We-toon: A Communication Support System between Writers and Artists in Collaborative Webtoon Sketch Revision.

Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '22), 14 pages.

[a4] Jeon, H.*, Ko, H.-K.*, Lee, S., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).

Uniform Manifold Approximation with Two-phase Optimization.

Proceedings of IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS '22), 5 pages.

[a3] Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

> Measuring and Explaining the Inter-Cluster Reliability of Multidimensional Projections. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (In Proceedings of VIS '21), 28(1):551-561.

Jung, S., Choe, K., Park, S., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2021). [a2]

Mixed-Initiative Approach to Extract Data from Pictures of Medical Invoice.

IEEE Pacific Visualization (PacificVis '21), 111-115.

[a1] Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2021).

Progressive Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection.

EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis '21), 133-137.

Preprints & Publications in Progress

[b4] Shin, H., Lee, Y., Ko, H.-K., Kim, J. (2022). Enabling Prototyping of AI-infused UIs with Task-level Specifications. (In Progress)

[b3] Ko, H.-K., Park, G., Jeon, H., Jo, J., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2022).

Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works. Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

1/2

[b2] Choi, J.*, Song, J.*, Jeon, H., Kim, Y., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2022).

How Disentanglement Affects Users' Interpretation, Control, and Sentiment when Using Generative Models.

(Under Review)

[b1] Jeon, H., Aupetit, M., Lee, S., Ko, H.-K., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

(* denotes equal contributions)

Experience

06/2022-Present KAIST Interaction Lab (KIXLAB), Daejeon, Korea

Researcher, working with Dr. Juho Kim

10/2021-06/2022 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Scientist, Webtoon AI

04/2021-10/2021 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Intern, Webtoon AI

03/2019-08/2019 Human-Computer Interaction Lab, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern, working with Dr. Jinwook Seo

01/2019-02/2019 LG Electronics, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern, CTO Division

06/2018-08/2018 Wesleyquest Inc., Seoul, Korea

Research Associate

Honors and Awards

2022 Gary Marsden Travel Award (Full travel support for UIST '22)

2018 Big Data Forum President Award (3rd Place)—National Information Society Agency (NIA)

and Korea Big Data Forum

2018 AI Novel Writing Competition (2nd Place, Prize Money: 20M KRW)—KT Corporation and

Korea Creative Content Agency

2017 Academic Research Competition (2nd Place)—Hanyang University 2014-2019 Merit-based University Scholarship (6 semesters)—Hanyang University

Academic Services

Paper ACM CHI ('22)

Reviewing IEEE PacificVis ('20, '21)

Student ACM UIST ('22)

VOLUNTEERING